# Jazer Barclay

Portfolio: www.jazer.dev Email: contact@jazer.co.uk

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jazer-barclay Mobile: 07759 228812

### **Profile**

Second year Computer Science student at the University of Brighton focusing on scalable full stack development, scalable infrastructure and machine learning; currently looking for an industry placement.

Self-motivated and disciplined with a strong knowledge of Linux, Java, PostgreSQL, NodeJS and Git from over 10 years of education and formal work experience combined.

### **Technical Skills**

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- NodeJS
- Linux
- Java
- PostgreSQL
- Git & GitHub
- CD / CI & Agile

### Relevant Experience

**Project: Full-Stack Website and Blog** ( www.jazer.dev )

Duration: January 2021 - September 2021

Technologies Used: Ubuntu, Nginx, Docker, React, HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, GitHub

- Deployed a scalable docker infrastructure on a cloud hosted ubuntu server
- · Created a script to generate wildcard certificates for all subdomains
- Personal portfolio auto-deployed using GitHub Actions on mainline commit
- API backend using NodeJS and PostgreSQL to serve data
- React frontend interface populates data using an internal route to the API
- Version controlled using git and hosted on GitHub

#### Tora Tech – Lead Developer & Senior Technician

**Duration:** July 2017 – June 2020

Full time software developer designing and building bespoke websites **driving sales up by up to 20%** and providing a greater online presence for new businesses.

Supported businesses and residential customers with technical support via remote assistance and on-site for hardware repairs, upgrades and installations.

Maintained Linux and Windows Servers facilitating 99% uptime with the remaining 1% being for scheduled maintenance for hardware upgrades.

#### Terinea Ltd - Software Developer & IT Support

Duration: June 2014 - March 2017

Full time Java software developer **building an enterprise retail platform deployed across the UK** using Java, PostgreSQL, Google Web Toolkit, Tomcat, Ant and SVN.

To improve internal development, I created a lightweight Java application for generating user interfaces which automatically integrated with database tables halving interface development time and reducing maintenance time by employing a standard format.

## **Education and Qualifications**

Computer Science (BSc Hons), University of Brighton (2020 - 2024)

- Achieved 70% and above in all first year modules, including 100% in computing technologies and an 81% year average
- **Student representative** for first year, assisting students through remote learning and providing personal support in my spare time
- Took the role of **project leader** in first year modules managing a team of 3 achieving a **72%** final grade building a website

#### Java 8 Course, London (December 2015)

• Completed a week intensive course covering core Java, lambda functions, network beans, agile development and git version control.

#### Bexhill College, Bexhill-on-Sea (2011 – 2014)

• A Levels: Electronics (B), IT (C), Computing (D)

### **Claverham Community College, Battle** (2006 – 2011)

• GCSEs: 10 at grades A - C including Science (A), English (B) and Maths (B)

### Interests

I use to see cycling as just a means of transport and over the years I have found that it provides me more than just that. It helps me clear my mind and keeps me in good shape which is very much required when working stationary for extended periods of time.

Audiobooks have provided me a hands free way of absorbing new information without the fatigue on the eyes and is now one of my favourite habits to indulge in. It's an amazing source of knowledge in a more accessible and digestible form. "The power of habit" had a profound effect on me and has inspired me to start "Atomic habits" and "The 5am club".

# References

**Personal Tutor**, University of Brighton Lecturer and Personal Tutor Mithras House, Lewes Rd, Brighton, BN2 4AT [staff member email]@brighton.ac.uk | [Phone Number Here]

**Robin Tweedie-Walker**, Terinea Ltd Managing Director Unit 13 Napier House, Elva Way, TN39 5BF robin@terinea.co.uk | 01424 229950